Guide to the College of Engineering records ARCH057
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
College of Engineering records
1956-1998
Undated
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
University of Hartford. College of Engineering
ARCH057
1.35 Linear Feet (4 containers)
This collection contains records from the College of Engineering from 1956-1998.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to all researchers.
Historical Note
Since its founding as the College of Engineering, this school has expanded to offer courses in all phases of engineering including acoustics, biomedical, civil computer, electrical, environmental, and mechanical. In 2003, the College of Engineering and the Ward College of Technology combined to become the College of Engineering, Technology, and Architecture. Also in 2003, construction of the, Integrated Science, Engineering and Technology (ISET) complex began construction. In the fall of 2004 the Master of Architecture program was inaugurated.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists primarily of subject files including annual reports, accreditations and self-studies, public information, correspondence, histories, buildings and facilities records, and some material about individual faculty members. The collection also includes photographs.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into three series: I. Subject Files, II. Photographs, and III. Duplicates.
Photographs; Scrapbooks; Buildings; University of Hartford. College of Engineering
- Subject Files, 1958-1998
  - Accreditation Report, 1974-1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Accreditation Report to the Connecticut state Department of Education, 1965 Mar (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The American Revolution in Diesel Fuel Injection, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Annual Report, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Annual Report: Division Of Research, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Building of the College of Engineering, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Committee for the Engineering Building, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Dana and UT Hall Scrapbook, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Educational requirements- Science and Engineering Buildings, 1964 JUN 17 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Engineering Applications Center, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Faculty, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ground Breaking Ceremony, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
  - Greater Hartford Council on Economic Education, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Hemond, Conrad Joseph and Obituaries, 1972-1973, 1996; 1996 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - History, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - History, By Peter W. Kalika, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Lewis, T. Skipwith, 1983 Mar 02 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Manpower Conference, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Mays, Marion: First Women To Receive Engineering Degree, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - NASA Grant, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Newsletter, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - News clips and Press Releases, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 23, Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Projections and Recommendations, 1985 Sep (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Public Information, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Report of the Committee on the Future of Engineering Education, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Research Division, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Research Institute, 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
  - Science Development Program, 1964 Dec 02 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Self Study, 1988 Jun 01 (Box 2, Folder 10, Box 3, Folder 1-3)
  - Students, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - United Technologies Hall Dedication, 1979 Sep 16 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Zerban H., 1971 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Zerban, Alexander H. (Dean of Engineering School), 1970 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Photographs, 1956-1983
  - Clarke, Richard G., Undated (Box Shared Photograph Box 4)
  - Colt Building, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 8, Box Shared Photograph Box 4)
  - Committee for the Engineering Building, 1978 Jan, Undated; Undated (Box Shared Photograph Box 4)
  - Conrad J. Hemond, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Dana and UT Hall Scrapbook, Undated (Box Shared Photograph Box 4)
  - Dean Zerban H., 1960 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Lewis, T. Skipwith, 1983 (Box Shared Photograph Box 4)
  - Price Waterhouse CFA Workshop, 1979 Aug (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Proposed Site for the College of Engineering, Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Students, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Duplicates, Undated
  - Dana and United Hall Scrapbook, Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Duplicates, Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)